“创始吸血鬼”前情提要
REBEKAH: Previously on
The Originals...
这座城市曾经是我的家
我要夺回来
This town was my home once.
I want it back.
喝了吧，只有这样我才能让你看到
你应该看到的真相
Drink. It's the only way
I can show you what you need to see.
克劳斯只真正
REBEKAH: There's only
ever been one man
害怕过一个人
我的父亲麦可
Klaus has truly feared.
my father, Mikael.
- 我们要你找到麦可
- 没问题
-We'd like you to find Mikael.
-Of course.
你必须要看到
现在你可以复仇了
You needed to see it.
And now you can take your revenge.
走吧，尽快逃走吧，越远越好
Go. Run as far
and as fast as you can.
恐怕你是被困住了
I'm afraid you're trapped.
边界咒语
真祖可以进却不能出
Boundary spell. The Originals can enter
but they can't leave.
蕾贝卡！
珍惜你仅剩的几口气吧
Rebekah!
Cherish the breath in your lungs!
这是你最后的机会了
It'll be your last.
没事的，这只是暴风雨而已
Hush now.
It's just a storm.
别害怕，我不会让它伤害你的
Don't be afraid.
I won't let it hurt you.
尼克，别走
Nik, don't go.
这是我为父亲刻的
I carved it for Father.
是一个勇敢的骑士
It's a brave knight.
现在你也能变得勇敢了
Now you can be brave too.
你会陪着我直到暴风雨过去吗？
Will you stay with me
until the storm ends?
我会永远在你身边，蕾贝卡
无论发生什么事
I will always stay with you,
Rebekah, no matter what.
蕾贝卡！
KLAUS: Rebekah!
- 快走
- 不准走
-Walk away.
-Don't move!
- 赶紧走吧
- 我做不到，我们被困在这里了
-Leave us now.
-I can't. We're stuck here.
以利亚，白橡树木桩在他手上
Elijah, he has the white oak stake.
这是我特地为你准备的，妹妹
I brought it for you, sister.
离开他的视线
ELlJAH: Get out of his sight.
你待在这里只会激怒他
Your presence here
only serves to anger him.
让我来对付他
Leave him to me now.
我以兄弟的身份请求你
Now, I'm asking you
brother to brother.
结束这场闹剧吧
We end this nonsense now.
你要站在叛徒那一边吗？
You would side with that traitor?
我没有选边站
I am not choosing sides
但我绝对不允许你伤害我们的妹妹
but I will not allow you
to hurt our sister.
反正我们也走不出这个墓地，以利亚
We cannot leave this cemetery,
Elijah.
你觉得你还能保护她多久？
How long do you think
you can defend her?
只要我还活着
As long as it takes.
我就会用尽任何手段保护她
And by whatever means necessary.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）
剧名：再会纽奥良
无论如何，一定要让自己活着
主演：约瑟夫摩根
MARCEL: Do whatever it takes.
Just stay alive.
我保证我一定会救你出去的
I promise you,
I'll get you out of there.
我从没见过他这个样子
I've never seen him
like this before.
他已经完全被愤怒冲昏了头
He's out of his mind with rage,
up all night
一整晚都在吼着各种难听的话语
howling one obscenity-laced
tirade after the next.
他会杀了我的
He's gonna kill me.
好吧，那你尽量离他远点
主演：丹尼尔吉利斯
All right. Stay as far away from him
as you can.
这主意真不错
Well, that's a brilliant strategy
但那个死贱人莎莉丝特
but given that that dead bitch, Celeste,
把我们困在这里，直到下次月亮升起
主演：克莱儿荷特
has trapped us in here
until moonrise,
这可能不太容易做到
my options are somewhat limited.
我不会把你丢在里面不管的
主演：菲比托金
I'm not leaving you in there.
黛维娜会找出咒语的漏洞
主演：菲比托金
Davina will find a loophole,
get you out early.
提前救你出来
然后我们就能一起离开这里
Then we can all go together.
如果克劳斯追来，我们就给他好看
主演：查尔斯麦可戴维斯
If Klaus comes after us,
we will take him
on one hell of a ride.
这几个世纪来
I lived for centuries
looking over my shoulder,
我一直提心吊胆，时刻都在准备逃跑
主演：莉雅派普斯
ready to run at a moment's notice.
我又要回到那种生活了吗？
Am I to go back to that?
晚点再担心这个吧
再给我一点时间
Worry about that later.
Right now, just buy me some time.
我保证，我会救你出来的
I promise you,
I'll get you out of there.
嘿，小黛，感觉怎么样？
主演：丹妮儿坎贝尔
Hey, D, how you feeling?
我给你带了点东西
Got you some stuff.
有机香皂和香氛蜡烛
还有一些薰香
Organic soap and scented candles,
some incense.
希望这些能帮你尽快找回
原来的自己
Just trying to help you get back
to feeling, you know, yourself.
我听说，女巫们正在庆祝
Word on the street is,
the witches are celebrating.
收获祭中献祭的四个女孩
已经有三个复活了
Three out of the 4 girls sacrificed
in the Harvest have come back.
第一个是你的朋友莫妮克
然后是另一个女孩，现在是你
First, it was your friend Monique
and then another girl, now you.
我听说，另外两个女孩说
制片：兰斯安德森
What I hear, the others are saying
在她们死去的时候
that the ancestors were with them
祖先们一直陪伴着她们
与她们交谈，教导她们
while they were dead, you know,
talking to them, teaching them.
她们说自己变得比以前更强大
They say they're stronger than ever.
你也是这样吗？
Was it like that for you?
制片：邦妮怀斯
不是的，那里什么都没有
No. There was nothing.
只有无尽的寒冷、空虚和黑暗
It was cold, empty, and dark
and it went on forever.
我很抱歉，小黛
编剧：麦克纳度奇
-I'm sorry, D.
我不想谈这些
编剧：麦克纳度奇
-I don't want to talk about it.
求求你，马赛尔
导演：杰西瓦恩
Please, Marcel,
别逼我
don't make me.
你已经这样好几个小时了
有什么意义呢？
ELlJAH: You've been at this
for hours, to what end?
尼克劳斯，我跟你从小打到大
我了解你
Niklaus, I know you
and I grew up fighting you.
我不会被打倒，也不会被说服
I can't be beaten
nor can I be persuaded.
你过不了我这关的
You cannot get past me.
我可以的
KLAUS; I could get past you
只是可能要踏着你的尸体过去
although it might have to be
over your dead body.
你用那把刀桶了我
You did stab me with that blade,
让我承受了数小时无以名状的疼痛
forcing me to endure hours
of unspeakable pain.
或许我该把愤怒转移到你身上
Perhaps I should direct my rage
toward you.
你真该看看你自己
You should see yourself.
充满杀意的神情，自以为是的姿态
The murderous expression,
the self-righteous posturing.
你就跟父亲一样
You look like Father.
我不是他
I'm not him.
我的愤怒源自蕾贝卡的背叛
Rebekah's betrayal
justifies my anger.
而他只是全然的疯狂
His was that of a madman.
你从没受到过他残忍的对待
You were never the recipient
of his cruelty!
你们两个没有，柯尔没有，芬恩也没有
你们都没有
None of you were,
not Kol, not Finn, none of you!
我想你可能已经忘记他真正的样子了
I think you've forgotten
what he was truly like.
不
No.
我没有忘记
I have not forgotten.
稳住
深呼吸
Be still.
Deep breath.
准备好
就是现在
Hold.
Now.
你的瞄准有进步
下次就能射中了
Your aim is improving.
Next time.
你居然还鼓励他，以利亚
MAN: You encourage him,
Elijah,
但他一天比一天更差劲
but he grows more pathetic
every day.
- 我才不差劲
- 不许顶嘴
-I'm not pathetic.
-Do not talk back to me.
你也没资格拿着这件武器
You're not man enough
to hold this weapon.
如果你不会打猎
你就毫无用处，只是个累赘
If you can't hunt,
you're nothing but a burden.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很遗喊泪眼汪汪的道歉填不饱肚子
It's a shame we can't feed
on sad-eyed apologies.
你就只会这点小伎俩
-It's your one and only skill.
-(CRlES OUT)
- 父亲，住手
- 退后，不然下一个就是你
-Father, stop.
-Stay back! Or you'll be next!
这孩子需要鞭策才能变强
The boy needs to be made strong.
尼克劳斯，我理解你的愤怒
Niklaus, I understand your anger
但我恳求你，做个比他更好的人
but I implore you,
be better than him.
做他做不了的事情
Do what he could not.
展现你的慈悲宽宏，而不是这残酷暴行
Demonstrate the grace of mercy
rather than this petty cruelty.
你要我对冤枉我的人展现慈悲
You ask me to show mercy
to one who has wronged me.
你真是一点都不了解我，是吧，哥哥？
You really don't know me at all,
do you, brother?
够了
Enough.
不论我做错了什么
Whatever I have done wrong,
我的罪过与你的相比简直微不足道
my guilt is nothing
compared to yours.
你想要复仇？好啊
You want revenge?
Fine.
但在那之前
我要看着你的眼睛告诉你
But before you have it,
I will look you in the eye
为什么是你的残忍与怨恨
and tell you
why it was your cruelty
让我们变成现在这样
and your spite
that led us to this.
那你请说吧
Well, go on, then.
畅所欲言吧
Speak your piece,
等你讲完了
and when you are finished,
我会赐予你应得的惩罚
I will grant you
the punishment you deserve...
就算我要先解决以利亚也无所谓
...even if I have to go
through Elijah to do so.
（乌苏林修女会）
（教堂 肃静区）
黛维娜
Davina?
马赛尔跟我说你在这里
Marcel told me you were up here.
你想跟我说说到底发生了什么事吗？
Do you wanna tell me what happened?
我死了
I died.
最开始，只有我一个人
但后来我听到了他们的声音
And at first, I was alone
but then I heard them.
在我耳边低语
Voices whispering to me.
谁？
Who?
祖先们
The ancestors.
他们对我很生气
They're so angry with me.
我用我的力量对付自己的族人
I used my power against my own
他们说如果我再滥用我的魔法
and they said
they'd do horrible things to me
他们会严厉地惩罚我
if I misuse my magic again.
一个世纪前，你背叛了克劳斯
So, a century ago,
you betrayed Klaus,
那个史上最危险的吸血鬼
the most dangerous vampire
in history
而唯一能救你的人
and the only one that can save you
就是你关在我阁楼里的那个女孩
is the girl
that you had locked up in my attic
但她现在就是个废人
but she's a basket case.
所以实际上，你唯一的希望
就是我的侄女
So, really, your only hope
is my niece,
能在精神上使这个年轻女巫复原
psychoanalyst
to resurrected teen witches.
差不多就是这个情况吧？
Does that about sum it up?
你都被女巫下了咒了还这么嚣张
Well, you're pretty smug
for a guy with a witch's hex.
黛维娜的魔法是你唯一的希望
Davina's magic
is your only shot at a cure.
我们别在这么明显的问题上绕圈子了
Let's not dance around the obvious.
这个诅咒会害死我的
This hex is going to be
the end of me.
每个咒语都有漏洞
Every spell has a loophole.
你比起任何人都该更有信心
And you, of all people,
should have more faith.
西恩死的时候我就已经失去信心了
I lost my faith when Sean died.
当我回到纽奥良时
When I came back to New Orleans,
我只希望能够阻止
I had nothing but hope
of preventing a war
吸血鬼和女巫之间的战争
between the vampires
and the witches
现在女巫失控了
and now the witches
are out of control
而你还让一个吸血鬼真祖控制了法语区
and you allowed an Original vampire
to take control of the Quarter.
不，没有希望了
No. There is no hope.
你没希望了，这个城市也没希望了
当然我也没希望了
Not for you, not for the city
and certainly not for me.
我们找回了黛维娜
We get Davina back,
她会找到方法打败克劳斯
she will find a way
to take down Klaus.
不，他马上就要从那陷阱里出来了
No. He's going to get out
of this trap that he's in
到那时，他会找到你
and when he does,
he's going to find you
然后把你撕成碎片
and he is going to tear you
into pieces.
你这是咎由自取的，马赛尔
You reap what you sow, Marcel.
开始吧
KLAUS: Let it begin!
对蕾贝卡米卡森的审判
The trial of Rebekah Mikaelson.
真让人松一口气，他控制了自己的自负
What a relief.
His ego is in check.
尽管说出真相吧
Just speak your truth.
我会确保他守规矩的
I'll make certain
he behaves himself.
你被控背叛自己的家人
You stand accused of betraying
your own blood.
你如何办解？
How do you plead?
我恳请你闭嘴安静地听
I plead you to shut up and listen.
你召唤了我们的父亲
你把他带来了我们的家园
You summoned our father.
You brought him to our home.
你还能有什么辩解？
What possible defense
could you have?
我知道他是你唯一害怕的人
I knew he was the only thing
that you feared
我想让你离开
and I wanted you to run.
因为你恨我
Because you hated me.
因为你可恨
你剥夺了我爱的自由
Because you were hateful.
You denied me the freedom to love.
这就是你的辩解吗？
Oh, so that's your defense?
你召来了麦可，那个毁灭者
吸血鬼猎人
You called Mikael, the destroyer,
the hunter of vampires
就因为我阻止你
奔向那些愚蠢的追求者
because I detained you
from pursuing some dull suitors.
你很残忍
控制欲强，还爱操纵人
You were cruel,
and controlling and manipulative.
我是想保护你
远离那些蠢货和寄生虫
I was trying to protect you
from imbeciles and leeches,
况且你的判断力这么差
not to mention
your own poor judgment.
那那个你所珍视甚至称作朋友的人呢？
And what about the one that you
loved enough to call friend?
你为什么阻止我爱马赛尔？
Why did you forbid me
to love Marcel?
不要提他的名字
Do not mention his name.
你到底怎么了？
What has happened to you?
我还记得那个时常逗我笑
I remember the sweet boy
送我礼物的温柔男孩
who made me laugh
and gave me gifts.
他热爱艺术和音乐
Who loved art and music.
我曾想要成为像你一样的人
I wanted to be just like you.
你怎会堕落到如此地步？
How could you have fallen so far?
你说你鄙视蕾贝卡的背叛
You say you despise Rebekah
for her betrayal
但没人比她支持你的时间更长了
and yet, no one has stood
by your side for so long,
连我都比不上
not even I myself.
也许是你忘记了
Perhaps it's you that's forgotten.
我还记得那天父亲发现你
I remember the day
that Father caught you
在用他的猎刀做棋子
whittling little chess pieces
with his hunting knife.
他狠狠地毒打了你一顿
He beat you so mercilessly
and for so long,
我都怕你撑不下去了
I actually feared for your life.
父亲，父亲，求求你
退后
-Father. Father, please.
-Stay back!
- 不要
- 住手，快住手
No! Stop it! Stop it!
我不会再让你伤害他了
I will not let you hurt him anymore.
你为了他跟我作对
You stand against me for him?
你把她描绘成一个忠诚的妹妹
So you would paint her
as a loyal sister
但她却为了跟马赛尔在一起而背叛我
but she betrayed me
out of lust for Marcel.
或许这就是为什么你护着她
Perhaps that was why you did it.
因为爱
For love.
或许我能平息愤怒
Perhaps I might temper my rage
只要蕾贝卡承认
她也是她愚蠢行为的受害者
if Rebekah will admit
she was a victim of her own idiocy,
承认她深爱的马赛尔利用她
that her great love Marcel used her
赶走了我们，夺走了我的城市
to oust this family
and to take my city!
马赛尔没有利用我
Marcel did not manipulate me.
你虽为他说话，但也难免疑惑
You defend him
and yet you can't help but wonder,
说不定我说的是对的
what if I'm right?
我们彼此相爱
We loved each other.
是你再三阻挠招致了你的毁灭
It was your refusal to respect that
that led to your ruin.
那在你离开纽奥良后
他怎么没来找你？
Then why didn't he chase after you
when you fled New Orleans?
是啊，我就说嘛
他在这里忙着窃取我的成果呢
Oh, yes. That's right.
He was here stealing what I built.
你想让我放弃马赛尔
请求你的原谅？
Do you want me to renounce Marcel,
to beg for your forgiveness?
休想
马赛尔没做错
I won't.
Marcel is not at fault.
- 是我召来麦可的
- 蕾贝卡，你必须…
-I called Mikael.
-Rebekah, you must--
是我把他引到纽奥良
I was the one
who brought him to New Orleans
都是因为你的恶毒
because of your wickedness!
我渴望爱和幸福
I wanted love and happiness
但两样你都不让我得到
and you denied me the freedom
to have either.
是的，我对父亲既恨又怕
Yes. I hated
and I was afraid of our father
但他没你那么可恶
but he was a lesser evil than you.
我的私生子哥哥对我步步紧逼
My bastard brother
who loomed over me,
就像你现在一样威胁着我
threatening me as you are now.
我要摆脱你
I wanted rid of you
如果再给我一次机会
我还是会这么做
and given the choice,
I'd do it again.
妹妹，快走
Sister, leave us.
- 我不走
- 我叫你快走
-I'm not going--
-I said, leave us, please.
你听不进她说的
You wouldn't listen to her.
那现在你就得来对付我了
So now you must deal with me.
我研究过伤痛带给人的影响
I've studied the effects
of trauma and abuse.
那些把你推上仪式的女巫
The witches who forced you
into that ritual,
她们欺骗了你，伤害了你
they've lied to you.
They hurt you--
卡蜜
Cami.
你在书本上学到的东西帮不了我
There's nothing you've studied
in some book that can help me.
好
Okay.
那不谈书本上的
Forget the books.
我来告诉你我从经历中学到的东西
Let me tell you
what I know from experience.
我哥哥死后，我以为
我永远都走不出来了
When my brother died,
I never thought I'd be okay again.
我天天以泪洗面，自责，也责怪他
I cried for weeks.
I blamed myself, I blamed him.
后来我突然意识到
我整个人被悲伤淹没
And then I realized all that sadness
was swallowing me up
我决心不再这样下去
and I made a choice
I wasn't going to let it.
你也可以做到，黛维娜
You can make that choice, Davina.
你说得好像这很简单
You say that like it's so simple
但那些女巫不会就这样让我走的
but the witches
aren't just gonna let me go.
她们不会放过我的
They're not done with me.
没有人能控制你
除非你允许他们这么做
No one can control you
unless you let them.
我怎么知道谁可以相信？
How do I even know who to trust?
我可以相信马赛尔吗？
Should I trust Marcel?
我后活以后他做的第一件事
The first thing he did
when I came back
就是想再次利用我去帮蕾贝卡
was try to use me again
to help Rebekah.
老实说，卡蜜
Be honest, Cami.
你是不是也有求于我？
Isn't there something
you want too?
是的，我叔叔病了
我想你能帮帮他
Yeah. My uncle is sick.
I thought you could help him.
我不是因为这个才来的
That's not why I'm here.
我关心你
I care about you.
- 我想帮你
- 你怎么帮？
-I want to help you.
-What can you do?
我复活后，耳边的声音
When I came back,
the voices I heard,
都是在说只有那些女巫可以帮我
they said the only ones
who could help me are the witches,
但在我冒犯了她们以后
她们恨我
but after what I did to them,
they hate me.
这叫我怎么回去求她们帮我？
So how can I go back
and ask for their help now?
我真是傻
REBEKAH: What a fool I am.
我还真以为黛维娜会来救我
I actually thought Davina
would come to the rescue.
我会找其他人
全城到处都有女巫
I'll get someone else.
Whole town is full of witches.
但她们都鄙视你
All ofwhom despise you.
我会想出办法
I'll figure this out.
你这段时间就别再激怒克劳斯了
Meantime, just don't piss Klaus off
any more than he already is.
为时已晚
It's a little late for that.
我已经再次激怒他了
I may have provoked him further,
但我已经不在意他的那些谴责
but then, I didn't much care
for his accusations
他说你诱导我把麦可引来
that you seduced me
into bringing Mikael.
拜托，我绝不会那么做的
Wait a minute.
I would never do that.
我们差点就成功了
We almost got away.
如果我们坚持走下去的话
Ifwe just kept going,
我们现在就可以浪迹天涯了
we could be anywhere
in the world by now.
克劳斯或许能追杀到我们
Klaus might've found us
and killed us,
反正他都会那么做
but he'll do that, anyway.
但最起码能先共度短暂的美好时光
Would've been nice
to have a little happiness first.
他不会杀你的，你是他妹妹
He's not gonna kill you.
You're his sister.
而你就像他的孩子
And you're like a son to him
但相信我，他真的会杀了你
and, believe me,
he means to kill you.
知道吗，我从未认真思考过死亡
You know, I've never much thought
about dying,
对于永生的人来说可能倒是种恩赐
one of the perks
of being immortal, I guess.
前一分钟还活着，下一分钟就死了
What an odd thing it is
to be here one minute
感觉好奇怪啊
and gone the next.
好吓人
Rather terrifying.
- 蕾贝卡
- 你快走吧，马赛尔
-Rebekah.
-You need to run, Marcel.
等到月亮升到天空最高处
克劳斯就自由了
When the moon reaches its apex,
Klaus will be free
他会对你做出
比要对我做的更恶劣的事
and he will do to you what
he's going to do to me, only worse.
立刻走，不要回头
Go now and don't look back.
接下来要怎么做呢？
KLAUS: So, what's it gonna be?
两个武器都在你手上
You hold both weapons.
图德的刀可以让我倒下
Tunde's blade
would put me down
而那根木桩可以永远了结我
but the stake
could finish me off for good.
我跟你不同
我没残杀手斗
Well, unlike you, brother.
I have no taste for fratricide.
我只是不能让它落到你手里
I only hold this
to keep it from you.
而它只是给我多了层保障
This is just my insurance.
你为什么要护着她？
Why must you defend her?
当蕾贝卡把麦可引来
她也同样背叛了你
Rebekah betrayed you as well
when she brought Mikael here.
因为她是我们的妹妹
Because she is our sister
因为我更愿意记住她过往的样子
and because I like to remember her
the way that she was
在我们变成这个样子之前
before we became what we became.
她是个天真的小女孩
乐观开朗，充满活力
ELlJAH: She was an innocent girl,
quick to laugh and full of life.
回忆过去只会让我对她的背叛更痛心
My memories serve
to make her betrayal more painful.
难道你就一点责任都没有吗？
Can you not then accept
some small part of the blame?
毕竟，尼克劳斯
-(SCOFFS)
-After all, Niklaus,
是你的残忍才让她做出了那些事
it was your cruelty
that led her to do what she did.
你不明白吗，以利亚
她不是想赶我走
Do you not see, Elijah?
She didn't mean to chase me off.
- 她想要我死
- 你错了
-She wanted me dead.
-You're wrong.
她一直恨我
你知道的
She has always hated me.
You know that's true.
你完全不知道，是不是？
You have no idea, do you?
你完全不知道她为了你做过什么
You have no idea
what she was prepared to do for you.
当我们的妹妹看到
When our sister
sees something
她觉得不公平的事时
that she perceives
to be an injustice,
她会很固执很冲动
有时候，甚至很危险
she can be stubborn, impetuous
and, at times, downright dangerous.
这些在她打算
And never was this more apparent
杀死我们父亲的那个夜晚尤为明显
than the night she tried
to kill our father.
这算什么？
What is this?
为了博得我同情的滥情小说吗？
Some melodramatic fiction
designed to garner my sympathy?
这是真的
It is the truth.
我当时也在场
I was there.
如果不是我拦着她
And she would have done it.
她为了保护你，早就下手了
All to protect you,
had I not stopped her.
我常想如果能再回到那一刻
I often wished
that I could revisit that moment,
亲手杀了他就好了
complete the task myself.
你为什么现在跟我说这些？
Why are you telling me this now?
尼克劳斯，有时候我们的妹妹
做事不经大脑
Niklaus, sometimes our sister acts
without thinking.
她脾气火爆
她很容易坠入爱河
She's short of temper.
She's quick to fall in love
但她爱你
but she loves you.
但你的恶意对待伤透了她的心
But your malicious treatment
has broken her heart.
她是做出了反击，召唤了我们的父亲
So, yes, she responded
by summoning our father.
那的确是个错误
Yes, that was a mistake.
但我不确定那是不是她的错
I'm not entirely sure
that I can blame her.
我确定
I can.
尼克劳斯，拜托你
Niklaus, so help me--
你真的要对抗我吗？
Are you really going to stand
against me?
别用那把破刀了
And not with that pathetic blade.
你总有一天要拔出来
You'd just have
to pull it out someday
那时我会恨你，就像现在恨她一样
and then I'd hate you
as I do her now.
你要是想保护蕾贝卡
If you want to protect Rebekah,
你就要用那根白橡树木桩
you'll need to use
the white oak stake.
我不听你胡言乱语
I don't have to listen
to this nonsense.
别装得好像你没想过一样
No, don't pretend
you haven't thought about it.
你看着我时
You look at me,
你看到的是在你身上你所憎恶的一切
and you see everything
you abhor in yourself.
虽然你穿着你华丽的西装
Sure, you dress it up
with your fancy suits
口袋里插着手帕
and your handkerchiefs.
尽管你戴着端庄的面具，能言善道
You, with your mask of civility
and eloquence,
但你跟我一样是个令人厌恶的存在
甚至更糟糕
you're every bit
the abomination I am or worse.
来啊，以利亚，来啊
Go on, Elijah.
Go on.
用那白橡树木桩
Use the white oak stake.
我没那么懦弱非得杀了你，尼克劳斯
I'm not so cowardly
that I have to kill you, Niklaus,
但如果只有你受苦才能保护蕾贝卡
but if I have to make you suffer
to protect Rebekah,
我不会手软的
that is what I will do.
看到了吧
(CHUCKLES)
You see?
我就知道你下不了手
I knew you couldn't do it.
你仍然坚信我可以被救赎
You still cling to the hope
that I can be redeemed
如果那狗杂种都能被救赎
那或许你就还有希望
and if the bastard can be saved,
then maybe there's hope for you.
好了
There.
现在你知道是什么滋味了
Now you know how it feels.
这话应该是我说才对
That was supposed to be my line.
现在这个在我手上
And now I have this.
谁生谁死我来决定
So I decide who lives
and who dies.
我要把那刀子拿出来
I'm taking out that blade.
那你得先杀了我
You'll have to kill me first
现在能杀我的东西就在你手上
and now you hold the means to do so.
为什么不完成你一世纪前要做的事呢？
Why not finish what you started
a century ago?
我不想要你死，我只想让你离开
I did not want you dead.
I wanted you to run.
骗子！你想要报复
Liar!
You wanted revenge.
你逼我背叛你
You drove me to betray you
现在你想要扭曲事实，让局势更加恶化
and now you want to twist it
and make it worse
这样你就能心安理得地杀了我
而不用承认自己的错误了
so you can justify killing me
instead of accepting your own fault.
我不过是爱上了你的朋友
All I did was love your friend.
你本可以为我们高兴的
You could've been happy for us
但你偏执地认为你会失去我们两个
but instead in your paranoia,
you feared losing us both.
正因为如此，你的确失去了我们
And, because of that, you did.
怨不得别人，尼克
只能怪你自己
There is no one else to blame, Nik,
only you.
马赛尔现在在哪呢？
And where is Marcel now, hmm?
我以为他是爱你的
I thought he loved you
但他却抛下你，让你和我困在一起
and yet he left you trapped
in here with me.
本市女巫的问题就是方向不明
GENEVlEVE: The trouble with the witches
in this city is they lack direction.
幸好，我们现在有新领袖了
我
Fortunately, our coven has found
a new leader. Me.
你想求我帮忙
减弱莎莉丝特的边界咒语
You ask a favor of me,
to lower Celeste's boundary spell
但你不再能控制女巫了
but you don't control
the witches anymore.
你想帮助女巫
你得跟我们休战
You wanna help your people,
you need to broker peace,
跟吸血鬼签订条约
a treaty with the vampires.
我可以帮忙
I can help.
我上次去谈判的时候
The last time I arrived
for a negotiation,
你还想杀了我
you tried to kill me.
我学到教训了
I learned my lesson.
如果不能打败他们，就跟他们做交易
If you can't beat them,
make them an offer.
交易如下
So here's the deal.
你现在帮我，我向你保证
You help me right now,
you have my word.
吸血鬼不再踏足女巫区
不再有杀戮
Vampires stay out of the Cauldron,
no more executions.
不错的开始
A nice start,
但如果你想要我减弱那咒语
but if you want my help
lowering that spell,
你就要把黛维娜克莱尔交给我们
you're going to have to give us
Davina Claire.
你们还没折磨够那女孩吗？
Haven't your people done enough
to that girl?
你要知道她死后受罪都是因为你
You must know it's your fault
she suffered in death.
她被祖先摒弃，因为她与你为盟
She was shunned by the ancestors
because of her alliance with you
但这都过去了
but all that's over.
现在我们欢迎她回家
Now we can welcome her home.
她会受到尊重
She will be revered
by her people
我会教她如何控制她的力量
and I will teach her
how to control her power,
给她一个安全的家
give her a home where she's safe,
不被吸血鬼包围着
not surrounded by vampires.
把黛维娜带来
Bring Davina to us
我会想办法破解莎莉丝特的咒语
and I'll find a way
to break Celeste's spell.
如果做不到
If not,
这么说吧，反正蕾贝卡的死活与我无关
well, let's just say that I won't be
the one to mourn Rebekah.
你对抗我？
KLAUS: You against me?
这不是公平竞争吧？
我是说
It's hardly a fair fight, is it?
I mean, perhaps,
如果马赛尔在这
也许你还有机会
if Marcel were here,
you'd stand a chance
但我想他已经找到另一个女孩了
but I expect
he's already found another girl,
毫无疑问更加年轻漂亮
no doubt younger and prettier.
你把别人的痛苦当成乐趣
还好奇我为什么会恨你
You take joy in other people's pain
and then you wonder why I hate you.
是的，那样的恨意让你做了那些事
Yes, and that hatred led you
to do what you did.
承认事实吧
承认你想要我死
Admit the truth.
Admit you wanted me dead.
我只想让你离开，仅此而已
随你怎么想
I wanted you to run that is all.
Despite your delusions.
以利亚正痛苦地躺着呢
我同意你去帮他
Elijah lies suffering
and I will allow you to help him.
你只需要承认就行
All you have to do is admit it.
- 你疯了
是的，是的
-You're insane.
-Yes! Yes!
我是邪恶无情的怪物
I am a vicious, heartless monster
所以你就召唤了麦可来杀我
承认吧
and so you summoned Mikael
to kill me. Admit it.
- 不是这样的
- 你知道自己做了什么，承认吧
-It's not true!
-You know what you did. Admit it.
- 我没有
- 你就是想要我死！
-I didn't.
-You wanted me dead!
承认吧
Admit it.
也许是的
Maybe I did.
尼克，我…
Nik, l--
你没刺中我的心脏
You missed my heart.
也许是吧
Perhaps I did.
也许我从没想过要杀死你
Or perhaps
I never meant to kill you.
也许我只是想让你感受一丁点
父亲来找我时
Perhaps I just wanted you
to feel a fraction the fear I felt
我所感受到的恐惧
when father came for me.
你自己知道真相吗？
Do you yourself know the truth?
我知道这点
I know this.
你怪我做尽坏事
You accuse me of being evil
但你却是密谋想要
and yet you are the one
who conspired
杀死自己亲哥哥的人
to kill your own blood.
你让我们过得生不如死
你折磨我们
You made our lives a living hell.
You tormented us.
我爱我的家人
I love my family.
爱你，爱以利亚
You, Elijah.
我爱你们所有人
I loved all of you.
我知道我不易相处
但这不是我造成的
I know I can be difficult
but I did not make myself this way.
是麦可毁了我
It was Mikael who ruined me.
他也毁了我
He ruined me too.
你却忘了这点
That's what you forget.
几个世纪后，我们每个人都伤痕累累
Centuries later,
each of us is broken.
你愤怒多疑
You with your anger and paranoia.
我害怕被抛弃
Me with my fear of abandonment.
而可怜的以利亚
And poor Elijah.
他不顾自己，全心全意为我们每一个人
He dedicates himself to everyone
but himself.
我们是这世上最强大的生物
We are the strongest creatures
in the world
但却被摧残得无法痊愈了
and yet we are damaged
beyond repair.
我们没有希望地活着
却永远不会死去
We live without hope
but we will never die.
被诅咒者说的就是我们
We are the definition of "cursed."
直到永远
Always and forever.
- 她怎么样了？
- 情绪低落
-How is she?
-Depressed.
她需要真正的帮助
She needs real help,
也许待在一个能够让她得到全天候照顾
maybe a stay in an institution
和医疗帮助的地方最好
where she can get round-the-clock
care and medication.
不不，她待在那样的地方
No, no, no.
She stays in a place like that,
就永远出不来了
she is never getting out.
你有更好的主意吗？
You have a better idea?
我们可以把她送回她的族人身边
We take her back to her people.
什么？
What?
有更重大的事要发生了，卡蜜
There are bigger things
going on here, Cami.
这是她唯一的机会
It's the only chance that she has.
- 我们得好好商量这件事
- 我不是在请求你的允许
-We have to talk about this.
-I'm not asking for permission.
现在我们扯平了
Now we're even.
- 那我们说定了？
- 黛维娜在睡觉
-So we have a deal?
-Davina is asleep.
等她醒来，我会向她解释一切
When she wakes up,
I'll explain everything.
然后我会带她过来
Then I'll bring her here.
在此期间，我们得削弱那个屏障
Meantime, we need
to lower that barrier.
莎莉丝特施了一个强大的咒语
Celeste cast a powerful spell.
算你走运，她死了
Fortunately for you, she's gone.
她的力量重新回到大地
Her power bled back into the earth.
现在我可以引导它，操纵它
Now I can channel it, manipulate it.
这需要费点工夫
但我对我做的事很在行
It'll take some doing but then,
I'm pretty good at what I do.
还有一件事
我需要你治好神父
One more thing,
I need you to fix the priest.
抱歉
Sorry.
像那样的诅咒
如果让它有时间生根
A hex like that,
if it's had time to take root,
就没办法撤销了
there's no undoing it.
好吧，把蕾贝卡救出来就行
Fine.
Just get Rebekah out.
我得撤销整个咒语
I'll have to undo the entire spell.
不可能让一个真祖出来
而把其他人留在里面
Can't let one Original out
without letting them all out.
没关系
It doesn't matter.
只是你要知道
即使克劳斯自由了
And just so you know,
even if Klaus is free,
如果你敢伤害黛维娜…
if you hurt Davina in any way--
马赛尔，结束了
你输了
Marcel, it's over.
You lost.
试着留点尊严吧
Try and have a little dignity.
我们还是被困在这里
We're still trapped in here.
你想对我做什么，现在就动手吧
Whatever you're going to do to me,
do it now.
你说父亲毁了我们
You said our father ruined us.
我不禁好奇
如果是他的父亲毁了他呢？
And I can't help but wonder,
what if his father ruined him?
屏障撤销了
The barrier is down.
我知道你恨我，但木已成舟
I know you hate me
but what's done is done.
其实不然
What's done is never done.
都留在我们心中
It remains within us,
变成我们给自己的故事
这样我们就知道我们到底是谁
the story we tell ourselves
so we know who we are.
邪恶的父亲
私生子
Vicious father, a bastard son...
还有一个背叛他的妹妹
...and the sister who betrayed him.
也许是时候开始新的故事了
Perhaps it's time for a new story.
你想要什么，蕾贝卡？
What is it you want, Rebekah?
打从儿时起我就想要的东西
Same things that I have wanted
since I was a child.
我想要一个家，一个家庭
I want a home.
I want a family.
想要有人爱我
我想要活着
I want someone to love me
and I want to live.
那去吧
Then go.
走得远远的，永远不要回来
Go far away and never come back.
我们已经伤痕累累，无法待在一起
We are far too damaged
to remain together,
不像是家人
更像是一堆易爆的材料
Iess a family now
than a volatile mix of ingredients.
纽奥良将是我的
New Orleans will be mine.
我要在这里养育我的孩子
在这个你从我手中夺走的城市里
I will raise my child here
in the city you took from me.
毫无疑问，以利亚会选择留下
No doubt,
Elijah will choose to stay.
但是你，妹妹
But you, sister...
你自由了
You are free.
我就想会在这里找到你
I thought I might find you here.
我只是来收拾最后一些
I just came to collect
the last of my things
没被烧成灰烬的东西
that didn't burn to ash.
我很快就会离开
I'll be leaving shortly.
我想你不会想要跟我一起走
I don't suppose you have any desire
to join me.
我衷心希望你能找到你在寻找的一切
I do hope you find everything
you're looking for.
以利亚，在我把麦可引来时
Elijah, when I brought Mikael,
我绝对没有想要伤害你
I never for a second meant
to hurt you.
我知道
I know.
但我确定克劳斯是真的想杀死我
And I was certain
that Klaus meant to kill me.
不论是他从没有真正做过
还是他改变了主意
Whether he never really did at all
or he changed his mind.
也许在内心深处
Maybe somewhere deep down,
他仍是我们曾经熟悉的兄弟
he still is the brother
we once knew.
很深，不过…
Buried deep, but...
那个他还在
...he's still in there.
帮他走上正轨
Help him find his way.
是什么原因让你们这么多人
在我家闲逛？
Is there a reason why you lot
are loitering in my home?
我叫他们来的
MARCEL: I asked them
to be here.
你和我需要公开地解决这事
You and I need to settle this
out in the open.
我还以为你早就跑了
I thought
you would've run off by now.
是啊，不过这可是我的城市
Yeah.
Well, this is my town.
你也许想要我请求你宽恕
但我毫无歉意
You may want me to beg forgiveness,
but I'm not sorry.
我也许没有能力打败你
但我到这里来面对你
I may not be able to beat you,
but I came here to face you.
在我的人面前做个了结
To end this in front of my people.
如果你要因此杀了我
就动手吧
If you're gonna kill me for that,
get on with it.
晚安
Good evening.
我想我就不用自我介绍了
I trust I need no introduction.
这里曾是我的家
毕竟
After all, this was once
my family home.
我要收回这里
今晚
Tonight, I'm taking it back.
你在这里的权力已被取消
Your privileges here
have been revoked.
马赛勒斯，出于对我妹妹的尊重
Marcellus,
out of respect for my sister,
我这次就手下留情
I will grant you this one mercy.
允许你留着你的小命
I will allow you to keep your life.
然而，你被驱逐了
However, you're hereby exiled.
如果我在法语区发现你的踪迹
If I so much as find a trace of you
in the French Quarter,
你不会有好下场的
明白了吗？
it will not end well for you.
Do you understand?
就这样
走吧
That is all.
Run along.
干得好，哥哥
Nicely done, brother.
你说话的语气开始像我了
真不错
You're beginning to sound like me.
I'm impressed.
我在想
REBEKAH: I was thinking.
我母亲被供奉，埋葬在这里
My mother was consecrated
and buried here.
她被永远束缚在这片土地了
但我没有
She is forever bound to this land,
but not me.
我终于自由了
I'm finally free.
你呢？
And you?
你的哥哥们一来，就把这里据为己有
Your brothers came in this town
like they own the place,
好像我是他们的仆人
Iike they own me.
夺走了我的家、我的人
Took my home, my people,
我的一切
everything.
我不能就这么跑掉
I can't just run away.
我没要求你这么做
I'm not asking you to.
我不是傻瓜
I'm not a fool.
我知道你有多爱这城市
I see how much
you love this city,
而我不是那种愿意和人分享的女孩
and I am not the kind of girl
who likes to share.
我真心希望你建好了我们的家
I do wish
you had finished building our home.
即使我从未去过
Even if I'd never set foot inside...
如果经历这一切之后
...it would have been nice
还有美好的东西能留下来
那就真的太好了
if there was something beautiful
left standing after all of this.
再见，马赛尔杰拉德
Goodbye, Marcel Gerard.
要努力好好活着
Do try to stay alive.
蕾贝卡，你怎么来了？
Rebekah, what are you doing here?
我是来道别的
I came to say goodbye.
不是说好我们女孩要团结在一起的吗？
What happened to us girls
sticking together?
我和尼克达成了一个
要么死要么走的协定
Well, Nik and I came to a sort
of all-or-nothing arrangement.
我永远离开这里，他同意了
I leave town for good,
he allows me to.
真的没法拒绝呢
Can't pass that up.
和克劳斯待了一千年
(SCOFFS)
A thousand years with Klaus,
我想你应该享受几天假期
I guess you deserve
a few vacation days.
听着，关于尼克
他是个怪物
Listen.
About Nik, he is a monster.
千万不要惹他生气
Do not ever cross him,
但他真的想要从生活中得到更多
而不只是被畏惧
but he does want more from life
than to just be feared.
他受过太多伤，以至于迷失了自己
He's too broken to find it himself...
但我相信他还是有希望的
...but I do believe
there is hope for him
那就是你肚子里的这个孩子
in the baby that you carry.
说到你的孩子
And speaking of your child,
我们家族树敌无数
our family has no shortage
of enemies.
她将会继承一切
She will inherit all of them.
请你一定要小心
Please be careful.
你随时可以回来探望我们
You know you can always come back
and visit.
我一直知道应该对克劳斯
隐瞒一两个秘密
I've been known
to keep a secret or two from Klaus.
如果我没法回来
Well, if I can't,
你一定要告诉这个小丫头
you make sure
to tell that little girl
她疯狂姑姑贝卡的故事
stories of her crazy Auntie Beks.
让她知道
And let her know that...
尽管我不在
我一样非常爱她
...despite my absence,
I do love her very much.
片名：创始吸血鬼（第一季）